mamapedia.com 2019-04-18

# Mamapedia™

We use Ezoic to provide personalization and analytic services on this website, as such Ezoic's privacy policy is in effect and can be reviewed [here](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/mamapedia.com).  

Effective Date: 8/1/2013

Children (i.e. those persons under the age of 18), are not eligible to use any of the Company Sites without supervision. We thus ask that children do not submit any information to us. If you are under the age of 18 and want to use any of the Company Sites, you may only do so under the supervision of your legal parents or guardians.

### When Does The Company Collect My Information, Including Personally Identifiable Information?

Registration. When you register, the Company asks for your e-mail address, a user selected user name, and other information. Once you are a registered user you can update your profile and may be able to provide additional preferential information (e.g. professional and academic background information, contact information etc).

Special Contests or Promotions. The Company may occasionally present a special contest or promotion that is sponsored by another company. To qualify for entry in that contest or promotion, we may ask you to provide personal information. If we plan to share that information with the sponsor(s) or with others, we will provide a statement to that effect in the contest or promotion terms.

IP Address. An Internet Protocol (IP) address is unique string of numbers that is assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. Web servers automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We will use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our site. Your IP address also may be used to gather broad demographic and geographic information for advertising and other purposes.

Cookies. A cookie is a small data file that can be placed on your hard drive when you visit certain websites. We use cookies to collect, store and sometimes track information for statistical purposes to improve the services we provide. If you are a registered user, we will use a cookie to save your settings (such as, but not limited to, username and/or password) and to provide customizable and personalized services. These cookies do not enable third parties to access any of your personally identifiable information. Additionally, be aware that if you visit other websites you may be required to accept cookies. Advertisers and partners may also use their own cookies. Additionally, we use Google as a third party vendor of Advertising on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to you based on your visit to us and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy.](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) We do not control use of DART cookies or any other Advertiser or partner cookies and expressly disclaim responsibility for information collected through them.

Third-Party Advertisers. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [ Network Advertising Initiative - Consumer Opt Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

Links to Other Sites. The Company Sites contain links to other Web sites. The Company is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. The Company Sites may also link to web sites that feature Company trademarks and names along with trademarks and names of other companies. You should look at the privacy policy on that co-branded Web site, as the co-branded Web site may not be under Company’s control.

Information from Other Sources. For reasons such as improving member experience and providing customized communications to our users, the Company may receive information about you from other sources and add it to the information that we have received from you.

### How Is My Personally Identifiable Information Used By The Company?

Customized experience. The Company gathers user information to provide you with a customized experience on our sites. Your user information helps us tailor the content, services, goods and advertising to your current and future needs. For this reason, we may ask you to register or to provide personal information when you visit certain areas of the Company Sites, download free software, enter a contest, order products, or subscribe to a newsletter. If you choose not to register you may not have access to areas that require personal identification.

E-mail. If you register with our site, from time to time, we may e-mail you with informative messages about our services or third party products and services we believe may be of interest to you, such as new features and services, special promotions and updated information. The newsletters may contain code that enables our database to track your usage of the newsletters, including whether the email was opened and/or what links (if any) were clicked. We will combine that information to other information we have about you and may use that information to improve your site experience and/or provide customized e-mail communications to you.

### Who Does the Company Share My Information With?

Your privacy is of utmost importance to us. We therefore do not sell, rent or give access to your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your prior consent, except as provided below.

The Company may disclose information you provide if required to do so by law or if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process served on the Company; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of the Company; or (3) act in an emergency to protect someone’s safety.

From time to time, the Company may provide offers from particular merchants who, as part of the offer, request information on the customers who purchased the offer in order to aid redemption. In those cases, the Company will share some of your personal information with such merchants. Sharing this information may allow a merchant to market directly to you should they choose to do so. However, the Company will only share personal information with a merchant if you purchase an offer from such merchant. The Company specifically disclaims any responsibility or liability for the actions of such merchant. While the Company informs them that they are only permitted to communicate with you for the purposes of the specific promotion with the Company, the Company does not have any responsibility for the actions of the merchant, and the actions of the merchant are not within the Company’s control.

The Company may share your information with certain third parties who provide services or products on the Company’s behalf. For example, the Company may use third parties to perform functions on its behalf, like sending out and distributing the Company’s administrative and promotional emails. The Company may share your personal information with such third party service providers to fulfill orders, deliver packages, send postal or email, administer contests or sweepstakes, remove repetitive information on customer lists, analyze data, provide marketing assistance, provide search results and links, process credit card payments, operate the the Company’s websites, troubleshoot, and provide customer service. The Company may also share your personal information with third party service providers to accomplish the Company’s administrative tasks. For example, when you order a service, the Company releases your credit card information to the card-issuing bank to confirm payment for the service and, if applicable, releases your address to the delivery service to deliver the service. Likewise, we may release an Affiliate’s information to our bank to send out a payment. The use of your personal information by such parties is governed by the privacy policies of such parties and is not subject to the Company’s control.

We may gather demographic information from you (for example, your age, education level or household income) from time to time. We will not share that information in a manner that identifies you as an individual with any other entity, unless we specifically ask for your permission at the time of collection of such data.

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets, and, depending upon the transaction, your personal information may be one of the transferred assets. In the event that Company is acquired by another company, your personal information may be part of the assets transferred to the acquiring party.

### Use Of Other Members’ Information

As a user of the Company Sites you will have access to other users’ personal information. You agree to use this information solely for sharing and requesting referrals and recommendations. The Company and its users shall not tolerate spam of any kind. Accounts suspected of causing spam will be deleted immediately and such users shall not be allowed to register again. You are thus not permitted to contact any user of the Company Sites via email, marketing messages or other kinds of spam without receiving their prior consent. Please feel free to report any users you suspect of using the Site as a platform for spamming by contacting our [webmaster](https://www.mamapedia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#285f4d4a45495b5c4d5a6845494549584d4c4149064b4745).

The Company has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. These security measures include a firewall to prevent unauthorized access to our systems and maintenance of registration information in a secure database. Although we will exercise reasonable care in providing secure transmission of information between your computer and our servers, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to us over the Internet and we accept no liability for any unintentional disclosure. We will protect the transmission of credit card information through industry standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption.

### Compromise of Personal Information

In the event that your personally identifiable information is compromised as a result of a known or suspected breach of security, the Company will promptly notify you in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this privacy policy or as otherwise required by applicable law.

You can manage your email and notice preferences by logging into your account through the Mamapedia website by clicking on your name in the top right of the Mamapedia homepage. Then click on the Edit My Profile link, located to the right of your profile name. On the right hand side of this page you will see the Update My Email Preferences link. Click on this link and you will be shown your current Email preferences, adjust your settings to select the types of emails that you’d like to receive and then click Save Changes. It’s that simple! To adjust your email preferences now, go [here](http://www.mamapedia.com/edit_email_notification_prefs). You can also manage your subscriptions by following subscription management instructions contained in the commercial e-mails that we send you. Please note that even if you unsubscribe from promotional email messages, we may still need to contact you with important transactional information related to your account.

It is the Company’s policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to the Company’s website users via e-mail notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on the Company’s website page, as determined by the Company in its sole discretion.

We would like to receive your comments and questions about this Privacy Policy. Please address comments or questions regarding the Company’s Privacy Policy to us via e-mail or postal mail at:

[[email protected]](https://www.mamapedia.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#82f1f7f2f2edf0f6c2efe3efe3f2e7e6ebe3ace1edef)   
or   
Mamapedia   
128 N Pitt St, Suite 2   
Alexandria, VA 22314   
or   
(888) 608-8465 

### Acceptance of Privacy Policy

Your use of the Company Sites, including any dispute concerning privacy, is subject to this Privacy Policy and Company’s Terms and Conditions of Use ([Terms and Conditions](https://www.mamapedia.com/static/terms_and_conditions)). By using the Company Sites, you are accepting the practices set out in this Privacy Statement and those Terms and Conditions of Use. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the changes on this page. Please check the revision date at the top of this page to determine if the statement has been modified since you last reviewed it. Your continued use of any portion of the Company Sites following posting of the updated Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the changes.
